Okay, so when most
people plan a video,
they open a document
and they just try
and write a script.
But that is just
going to be an
absolute nightmare because it's
like sitting in front
of a blank canvas
and trying to paint
a masterpiece with no
sketch or guide or
any idea as to
where to start. What
we need to do
is turn our video
into like a paint
by numbers outline that
takes all the chaos
and guessing out of
creativity and gives you
shape and structure and
clarity very easily. So
when you do come
to write this into
a script, it's just
a game of filling
in the blanks and
it's easy. So here's
exactly how I want
you to plan every
video and how I
do it too. So
the first thing is
you want to just
brain dump all the
points you think you
want to make on
a doc. Don't worry
about order. Don't worry
about structure. Just get
the raw thoughts out
of your head. And
you're going to need
to give yourself an
hour or so at
least to do this
because this is one
of the most important
parts of the video.
Then the next thing
you do is you
want to find outliers
on the topic that
have performed above average.
And you are going
to take their transcript
by using a Google
Chrome plugin, which I'll
link to below, and
you do it like
this and you just
copy it. And then
you go to Skyscraper
Bot, which I'll link
to below. It's not
in the custom AI
platform. And then what
you do is you
highlight up to 200
of the comments and
you paste them in.
Skyscraper Bot is now
going to tell you
everything that made this
video a hit. It's
going to tell you
what the comments loved,
what's missing, what confused
people, what the creator
spoke about. It's then
going to tell you
what made this unique,
feel new and inspiring.
And it's also going
to tell you what
it would include in
a video about it.
What you want to
do is take some
of that information and
add it to your
blog. And then you're
going to list the
kind of messy chaos
list. Then once you've
done that, we move
on to the next
step, which is basically
taking this information and
going, right, what's the
key things I need?
What can I delete?
And what do I
definitely need to include?
So we've gone from
mess to a little
bit more structured. Then
after that, we want
to start looking at
how do we bring
emotion and logic into
each of these points.
So this is where
it's going to get
hard. This is when
you're going to get
overwhelmed. You need to
start asking yourself, do
I just give them
a bit of emotion
at the start? Then
give them all the
steps or do I
give them emotion, logic,
emotion, logic. Now the
format planners I'm giving
you are going to
help a lot with
this, but this is
the part where you're
most likely to get
incredibly overwhelmed. And then
once you have that,
you want something that
looks like this, where
we have point one,
a little note on
the emotion side, and
then a little note
on the logic point
to a little note
on the emotion point
three, a little and
so on. Right. So
you can see that
doesn't look messy anymore.
So you can see
that it's really kind
of simplified down. Once
you've got that, you
are basically then in
a position where you
are ready to write
this up. And that
is kind of it.
Go and watch the
next video about writing
them. And then after
that, you're going to
have a task and
you have to do
some work and expect
that pain to shoot
up a bit. But
we do need to
get some reps in
and fail as fast
as we can until
this is going to
feel easier.